我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
巴里  你看到的就是神速力
Barry, what you're seeing is the Speed Force--
你的过去  现在和未来
your past, your present, your future
我说  爱瑞丝  你看上去美极了
Say, Iris, you look amazing.
谢谢你  托尼
Thanks, Tony.
他的皮肤变了  变成了某种金属
His skin changed. It turned to metal.
托尼可能是个恶霸  可他也不罪不至死啊
Tony might have been a bully, but he didn't deserve to die.
巴里  一直都有个人等你回家
Barry, you've always had someone to come home to.
我不禁这样想...
I can't help but wonder--
也许我们注定会在一起
maybe we were meant to be together.
你失去超能力了吗
You lost your powers?
我为了救沃利放弃了超能力
I gave them up to save Wally.
我可以创造相同的条件恢复你的速度
I can re-create the circumstances to get you your speed back.
让我们炸掉粒子加速器
Let's set up the particle accelerator.
巴里  他消失了
Barry--he's gone.
这不应该...
This wasn't su--
我没想...
I didn't--
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我们失去了他
We lost him.
不不不  他
No, no, no, no, he--
他可能在哪里晕倒了
he could've got knocked somewhere
甚至可能是跑过去的
or maybe even run there.
GPS没有任何发现
Nothing on the GPS.
建筑里到处都受到了电击
There were strikes all over the building.
杰西  下来一下
Jesse, come down here, please.
杰西
Jesse?
沃利
Wally?
我的天  沃利
Oh, God, Wally!
不不
No, no!
沃利  沃利  醒醒
Wally! Wally, wake up!
-不  -能听见我吗
- No! - Can you hear me?
-沃利  -杰西  杰西
- Wally! - Jesse, Jesse!
-杰西  -沃利
- Jesse! - Wally!
杰西
Jesse!
别再喊了
Stop yelling, please.
她的心脏停跳了
Her heart stopped.
Her heart stopped!
杰西
Jesse...
你没事吧
Are you okay?
杰西
Jesse!
跳了  她的心脏跳了
It's beating. Her heart's beating.
亨利是医生  让他看看
Henry's a doctor. He should see her.
我真高兴你安然无恙
I'm so glad you're okay.
他怎么了
Hey, what's with him?
是巴里
It's Barry.
巴里消失了
Barry's gone.
你还好吧  沃利
Are you good, Wally?
好吧  咱们应该回家  休息休息
Okay, we should get you home, get some rest, okay?
-我不明白  -没事的  我们走
- I don't understand. - No, it's okay. Let's go.
杰西
Jesse.
亨利  威尔斯的女儿在楼上
Henry, Wells' daughter is upstairs.
能量也击中了她
The energy hit her too.
她刚刚心脏停跳了
Her heart stopped beating.
亨利
Henry!
好吧
All right.
我看到他了
I saw him!
我看到巴里了
I saw Barry.
他还活着
He's alive.
乔
Joe?
很高兴见到你  巴里
Good to see you, Barry.
但我不是乔
But I'm not Joe.
-你不是  -不
- You're not? - No.
那所有这些呢
And all of this?
都不是真的吗
It's not real?
回到这里你感觉如何
How do you feel, being back here?
我感觉糟透了
I feel awful.
我们觉得在一个熟悉的地方
We thought you'd be more comfortable
和熟悉的人谈话
talking to someone who looked familiar
你会跟自在一些
and in a place you knew.
"我们"
"We"?
"我们"到底是谁
Who's "We," exactly?
这解释起来就有点麻烦了
That's a little hard to explain.
坐吧  巴里
Sit, Barry.
坐吧
Sit.
你对神速力了解多少
How much do you know about the Speed Force?
那是我力量的来源
It's the source of my power.
我也因此成为了极速者
It's what makes me a speedster.
你只说对了一部分
Yes... and no.
当宇宙大爆炸释放出第一颗亚原子粒子
When the first subatomic particle sprang forth from the Big Bang
形成了你眼前的世界
to form reality as you know it,
"我们"就已经存在了
we were there.
当质子最后一次衰变  停止震动
When the last proton decays, stops vibrating,
宇宙因此陷入热寂之中
and plunges the universe into heat death,
"我们"也会见证
we'll be there too.
难道您就是神速力
I'm talking to the Speed Force?
难道现在跟我对话的是
Isn't that like saying I'm having a conversation
重力  光...这类事物
with gravity or light or...
你先缓缓
You need a minute.
没关系的
It's okay if you do.
一时间肯定很难接受
It's a lot to take in.
这么说  您真的是
So you're saying I'm--I'm talking
我力量的来源
to the source of my power,
然而你长得恰好...
which just so happens to look like...
跟我的养父一样
my adoptive dad?
太不真实了
That's trippy.
刚才的对话是挺不真实的
We pretty much invented trippy here.
我不知道你为何把我带到这里
Look, I'm--I'm not sure why you brought me here,
但你得送我回去
but you need to send me back.
极速危及着我朋友们的生命
My friends are in danger from Zoom.
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
我不会让你回去的
You're not going back.
除非...
Not until...
除非什么
Till what?
除非你能抓住它
Until you catch that.
西斯科说巴里还活着
Cisco says Barry's still alive.
-他在哪  -不知道
- Where is he? - I don't know.
哈里  我用震波感觉到他在风暴中心
Harry, I vibed him in the center of a storm.
好像是一股涡流
It was, like, in, like, a vortex or something.
他在...
He's in--
他在神速力中
he's in the Speed Force.
-救他出来  -我...
- Get him out, damn it. - I--
难道你做不到吗
You can get him out, can't you?
我不知道能不能行
I don't know if I can.
亨利  过来
Henry, come here.
听着  你是唯一能帮得上杰西的人
Listen, you are the only one that can help Jesse.
我来审审威尔斯
Let me sit on Wells
直到他搞清楚自己究竟对巴里做了什么
till he figures out what the hell he did to Barry.
我觉得我们能把他找回来
I think we can get him back.
乔  我知道你很爱巴里
Joe, I know you love Barry, okay?
可你既有爱瑞丝  又有沃利
But you have Iris, and you have Wally.
我却只有巴里
Barry's all I have left.
我向你保证
I promise.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
幸好有你在
Thank God you're here.
这活一般都是凯特琳的  但...
Caitlin's usually the one doing this, but...
心率正常
Heart rate's normal.
反射和呼吸也没问题
Reflexes and breathing are fine.
按理说她该醒了
She should be waking up.
但却还没醒
She's just not.
巴里当时也是这种情况
It was the same with Barry.
上次粒子加速器爆炸后
Um, after the first accident,
他陷入了无人能解释的昏迷中
he was in a coma that no one could explain.
那你们是怎么处理他的
What did you do with him?
他们  其实是威尔斯把他带到了这里
So they brought him here-- well, Wells brought him here.
另一个威尔斯
The other Wells.
对  那个威尔斯其实是斯旺
Right, the Wells who was actually Thawne.
-艾尔伯德  不是艾迪  -对
- Eobard, not Eddie. - Right.
关系有点复杂
It's--it's complicated.
总之  在我们照料下  威尔斯...
Anyway, we took care of Barry while Wells--
是斯旺给他做了治疗
Thawne--treated him.
还有当时的治疗记录吗
Are there any records of that treatment?
也许能找到治疗杰西的办法
We might find clues how to help Jesse.
有  都在楼下的仓库里
Uh, yeah, they'd be downstairs in the storage room,
在停尸房里
in the morgue.
天啊  你们还有停尸房
Ew, you guys have a morgue?
不是那种普通的停尸房
Well, it's not like a morgue morgue.
不...其实就是个穷人的停尸间
It's not--it's like a poor man's morgue, really.
类似停尸房
Morgue-ish.
那你们能帮我找来吗
Would one of you go get them, please?
好  不过得有人陪我去
Okay, well, I'm not going alone.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧  的确是个停尸房
Okay, so it's a morgue morgue.
但我们总得找个地方存放死去的超能力者
But, you know, we had to keep the dead meta-humans somewhere.
可似乎你不止是把他们存了起来
Yeah, looks like you did a lot more than just store them.
冒牌威尔斯可能为了研究做了些
Fake Wells might've done a few dissections
解剖实验
for study purposes.
而他这种行为都没让你们怀疑
And this didn't tip any of you off
他可能暗地里很邪恶吗
that he might be secretly evil?
那段时间很多都无法解释
It was a crazy time, okay?
当时发生了很多事
We had a lot going on.
我跟你说
I'll tell you what--
斯旺做事这么有条理是件好事
it's a good thing Thawne was so organized.
你能不能别再把东西碰倒了
Would you stop knocking stuff over?
是你吧  我什么都没碰
You stop. I didn't touch anything.
好吧  随你怎么说
Okay, whatever you say.
找到了  就这个  巴里之前的档案
Okay, this is it. This is Barry's ex-file.
僵尸
A zombie?
真的吗
For real?
托尼
Tony?
不  不是托尼  再也不是了
Nope, not Tony-- not anymore.
-躲我后面  -你躲我后面
- Get behind me. - You get behind me.
托尼
Tony!
-这还真是出乎意料  -不
- Didn't see that one coming. - No.
僵尸钢梁  这
Zombie Girder. This--
爱瑞丝
Iris.
很高兴你办到了  巴里
We're glad you made it, Barry.
你不是爱瑞丝
Not Iris.
还是你
It's just you again.
请坐  巴里  请坐
Sit, Barry. Sit.
你总是站着
You're always on your feet.
你记得这个地方对吧
You remember this place,
我们第一次接吻的地方
where we first kissed?
是的  当然记得  不过不是和你
Yeah, of course, except that wasn't you.
我们以为让你来这个地方
We thought you'd find this place
见到熟悉的面孔  会好受些
and our appearance less upsetting.
然而你似乎不开心
Yet you seem upset.
我的朋友们  我的城市
My friends, my city...
我的整个世界都危在旦夕
my whole world is in danger.
极速在用他从我这夺走的力量为非作歹
Zoom is on a rampage with the power that he stole from me,
而你们却把我困在这里
and you are keeping me here.
你被赋予了一种罕见而宝贵的天赋
You were given a rare and precious gift,
而你却排斥这种天赋
and you rejected it.
不  我并没有排斥
No, I did not reject it.
我放弃力量是为了拯救他人
I gave up my powers to save someone's life--
为了当英雄
to be a hero.
为了找回这力量我差点搭上了我的命
I nearly killed myself trying to get them back,
然后你们就把我带到了这里
when you brought me here,
鬼知道这是哪里
wherever here is.
-那不是我们的本意  -好吧
- That's not what we meant. - Okay.
如果你们情愿把这种力量
If you would rather have given these powers
赋予他人
to somebody else,
那为什么要把这力量给我
why did you give them to me?
因为你是闪电侠啊  巴里
Because you're The Flash, Barry.
我们有新麻烦了
We got a new problem.
我们的粒子加速器实验似乎复活了
Our accelerator experiment seems to have reanimated
停尸房里某位死去的超能力者
one of the dead metas in our morgue.
就像起死回生那样"复活"吗
"Reanimated," like brought back to life?
只是能活动  你看过《行尸走肉》吗
Life-ish. You ever seen "The Walking Dead"?
就像"行尸走肉"一样
It's "The Walking Dead,"
但没有高级脑部功能
but without higher brain function
而且脾气很不好
and with major rage issues.
虽然还不确定它会不会吃我们的脑子
Still unsure if our brains are on the menu, though.
-是哪个  -托尼·伍德沃德
- Which one? - Tony Woodward.
全身变成金属的校园恶霸吗
The bully from school who turned into the metal man?
情况可不大妙   西斯科
That's not good, Cisco.
历史重演了
History repeats itself.
先是悲剧然后变成喜剧
First as tragedy and then as farce.
威尔斯  同为父亲  相信我
Wells, as a parent, believe me,
我对你经历的一切很是难过
I have nothing but sympathy for what you're going through.
你仔细听我说
Listen to me closely when I say to you,
我们现在同时面对着很多起火情
we got a lot of fires burning at the same time,
而如果我们齐心合力
and if we all work together,
我们或许能把它们都扑灭
we just might be able to put them out.
让亨利来照顾你女儿吧
Let Henry take care of your daughter.
我和爱瑞丝来处理钢梁复活的事
Me and Iris will handle this Girder situation,
而你和西斯科才是科学家
but you and Cisco are the scientists.
巴里现在不知道在什么鬼地方
You're the only one who can bring Barry back
但只有你们才有能力把他救出来
from wherever the hell he is right now.
拉蒙
Ramon...
把那些病例给亨利
give those medical records to Henry,
五分钟后在缺口房间里等我
and meet me in the Breach Room in five minutes.
我们要开始干活了
We've got work to do.
现在我们只需找到托尼
Now we just need to find Tony.
是啊  但愿他还没来得及杀人
Yeah, hopefully before he kills someone.
拜托
Come on.
星城的大肚子汉堡好吃太多了
Big Belly Burger in Starling City is way better.
这里的难吃爆了
This place sucks.
天呐  那是你的车吗
Oh, my God. Is that your car?
没错
Oh, yeah.
那是我妈的车
That's my mom's car!
这东西安全吗
So how do we know this is safe?
你这"安全"是指什么
Well, define "Safe."
就是我的脑袋不会被融化
Safe, as in my brain's not gonna melt.
不会  这只是个简单的反馈回路
No. It's a simple feedback loop,
拉蒙  知道吗
Ramon, all right?
当你对巴里用震波时
When you vibe on Barry,
你的脑波给我发送了一段所需的数据
your brain waves send me the necessary data
查出困住巴里的三维地区
to pinpoint whatever dimensional pocket
或是宇宙角落
or corner of the universe that Barry is stuck in.
然后只要缺口一打开
And then we electrically stimulate
我们就用电流来刺激你的前额皮质
your prefrontal cortex while opening a breach,
你能真实地看到巴里
which gives you physical access to Barry
成为指引他回家的灯塔
and lets you be the beacon to guide him home.
简单的反馈回路
Simple feedback loop.
抱歉  你说到电流刺激吗
I'm sorry. Did you say electrically stimulate?
拉蒙  你到底想不想把巴里带回来
Ramon, do you want to bring Barry back or not?
好吧
Okay.
目标锁定
And we have a lock.
我不明白
I don't understand.
如果我是闪电侠  那你们为什么这么对我
If I'm The Flash, then why are you doing this to me?
为什么我必须抓住这个东西
Why do I have to catch this-- this thing
然后你们才肯放我回去
before you let me go back?
听我说  你们的要求我都会照做
Please, look, I will do whatever you want.
快点放我回去  这样我才能帮我的朋友
Just let me go back right now, so I can help my friends.
巴里
Barry!
巴里  转身
Barry, turn around!
巴里
Barry!
那是什么
What is that?
那是你的朋友
Those are your friends.
他们想你回去
They want you to come back.
可以吗
Can I?
当然
Of course.
但如果你回去
But if you do,
超能力就没有了
it'll be without your powers.
抓住我的手
Take my hand!
来  抓住我的手
Do it. Take my hand.
选择权在你  巴里
The choice is yours, Barry.
巴里
Barry!
怎么回事
What is going on in here?
再坚持久一点  拉蒙
Just hang on a little longer, Ramon--
久一点
a little longer.
你要害死他了
Hey, you're killing him!
西斯科
Cisco!
西斯科  能听到我说话吗
Hey, Cisco, can you hear me?
我看到他了
I saw him.
巴里  他转身看着我
Barry-- he turned to me.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我没抓住他
I lost him.
不
No.
西斯科的超能力者警报程序一直在狂叫
Whoa, Cisco's meta-human alert app is going crazy.
托尼刚刚在吉特斯大肆破坏
Oh, Tony just trashed the hell out of Jitters.
那就奇怪了
Now, that is strange.
他撞倒了第四街和斯蒂文森街的消防栓
He knocks over a hydrant on 4th and Stevenson,
却没进楼里
doesn't go in the building,
然后在大贝利汉堡店前砸坏了一辆悍马
then smashes a Humvee in front of the Big Belly Burger,
也没进楼里
but doesn't go in the building.
结果轮到吉特斯的时候  他却进去了
Gets to CC Jitters-- he actually goes in.
吉特斯好像才是他的目标  可是为什么呢
Yeah, it's like Jitters was his target, but why?
当我在铁山监狱候审时
When I was in Iron Heights awaiting trial,
我有个狱友发誓终有一日  他一定要越狱
I had a cellmate who always swore he was gonna break out.
在审前听证会上  他抢走了副警长的抢
At a pre-trial hearing, he stole a deputy's gun
开警车逃跑了
and escaped in a police cruiser.
我会说到重点的  乔  我保证
There's a point to this, Joe, I promise.
这个可怜的蠢蛋本来可以逃之夭夭
Now, the poor, dumb bastard could have gone anywhere, right?
但两小时后  他却被人逮捕了
But he was apprehended two hours later.
知道为什么吗
Do you know why?
因为他去他老朋友家找他心爱的人
'Cause he went to his old girlfriend's house looking for her.
你认为托尼也是同一个目的
So you think that's what Tony's doing,
即使他变成现在这副样子吗
even in the state he's in now?
我认为人们都是有习惯的生物
I think people are creatures of habit,
有时习惯在某个程度上比意识思维更强烈
sometimes at a level stronger than conscious thought.
不  我觉得托尼没有女朋友
No, I don't think that Tony had a girlfriend.
就他向我献慇勤的方式来看
I mean, not the way that he was hitting on me when he--
那是在吉特斯的时候
he came into Jitters.
他又来找我了
He's after me again.
在他第一次找你之后
So, when he was after you the first time,
在吉特斯之后  你们在哪见的面
where'd you see him next, after Jitters?
家里
Home.
他是去家里带走你的
He came to our house when he took you.
沃利还在家
Wally's there now.
不不  老爸  这是好事
No, no, dad, this is good.
我们知道他在哪里  想要什么
We know where he is, and we know what he wants.
这就意味着我们知道如何打败他
That means we know how to beat him.
你说我们该怎么做
How do you propose we do that?
我当诱饵把他带到尖端科研实验室
We use me as bait to lure him back to S.T.A.R. Labs,
西斯科和威尔斯就能再一次
where Cisco and Wells can kill him.
杀了他
Again.
你这次又来假扮谁
Who are you pretending to be now?
我没这个时间
I don't have time for this.
不  你有  巴里
Yes, you do, Barry.
你有大把大把的时间
You have all the time in the universe
理论上讲
literally.
不  我没有
No, I don't.
你们怎么能站在那里口口声声
And how can you stand there in judgment
指责我抗拒自己的天赋
and accuse me of rejecting my gift?
你们知不知道自从被闪电击中
Do you have any idea how much I've done
我付出了多少
since I was first struck by lightning,
我用你给予的能力救了多少人
how many people I've helped with the power that you gave me.
还有我所牺牲的一切
What I've sacrificed?
我们当然知道
Of course we do.
你拯救了无数生命
You've saved countless lives.
现在你是世上唯一
And now you're the only thing
去和邪恶抗争的人
standing in between your world and unspeakable evil.
然而做了这么多
And yet for all of that,
你却从没来过这里
you've never been here.
诺拉·艾伦
真不敢相信他要来了
I can't believe he's coming here.
沃利  谢谢你
Wally. Thank you.
不客气
Don't mention it.
等等
Wait.
我一直想问你
I've been meaning to ask you.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
有点累  但是没事
Tired, but fine, I guess.
你没感觉到什么不同吗
So you don't notice anything different?
没有
Uh, no.
我想说  如果你感到害怕
I mean, I want you to know you can come and talk to me
或者对身体的变化有什么疑问
if you're scared or you have questions
你可以来和我说
about how your body's changing.
这个青春期谈话来得有点晚  老爸
I think you're a little late for the puberty talk dad.
我在网上看过了
I've seen the Internet.
看来我只会老一套了
Looks like I'm gonna have to do this the old fashioned way.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
沃利  上楼去
Wally, go upstairs.
上楼去  快
Please go upstairs, now.
老爸  你真觉得他是超能力者吗
Dad do you really think that he's a meta-human?
他被粒子加速器击中
Well he got zapped by the particle accelerator,
而且昏迷了  总要试试
and he was unconscious. It was worth a shot.
我送你的那个杯子
I gave you that mug.
他来了
He's coming.
-你确定吗  -知道吗
- You sure about this? - You know what?
两分钟前  我会说没问题
Two minutes ago, I would've said yes, absolutely.
但现在
But now
管他呢
what the hell?
托尼
Tony! Hey!
来啊  这边
Come on, over here.
你要去尖端科研实验室吗
You getting towards S.T.A.R. Labs?
-正要过去  -我在那里等你
- On my way. - I'll meet you there.
沃利  待在家  我很快回来
Wally, stay here! I'll be right back!
诺拉·艾伦
为什么带我来这里
Why did you bring me here?
你妈妈去世了  巴里
Your mother's death happened to you, Barry.
这也成就了你  但你真的
It made who you are, but have you accepted it,
接受失去她了吗
really accepted losing her?
所以你才不来这里
Maybe that's why you couldn't come here
因为显得太过真实
cause that would make it real.
我知道这是真的
I know it's real.
每天都历历在目
Every day I know it.
诺拉·艾伦
我有机会救她的
I had a chance to save her.
你看到了我的选择
You saw what I chose.
你能平静地面对这个决定吗
And you're at peace with that decision?
"平静"
"At peace"
谁能眼睁睁看着母亲死去
How could someone ever be at peace
还做得到平静呢
with letting his mother die.
决定自己的生命比她的更有价值
Deciding that his life was more valuable than hers?
诺拉·艾伦
你真的觉得你妈妈
Do you really think your mother
希望你为她去死吗
would've wanted you to die for her?
闪电侠所救的每条性命
And out of all the people the Flash saved
都是因为这个决定
as a result of that decision,
那他们呢
What about them?
他们的生命也有价值吗
Do their lives have value too?
我没必要听这些
I don't have to listen to this.
我要回家
I have to get home.
西斯科
Cisco!
那个僵尸还跟着你吗
Is that zombie still behind you?
好消息是  我们把托尼引回尖端科研实验室了
Good news is we lured Tony back to S.T.A.R. Labs.
坏消息是  我们把托尼引回尖端科研实验室了
Bad news is we lured Tony back to S.T.A.R. Labs.
不不  这是好事  提醒一下
No, no. This is good. Okay, sidenote--
你们俩估计会想站在房间的这一侧
you both might want to be on this side of the room,
尤其是如果身上带了首饰
especially if you're wearing any jewelry
或者体内有金属碎片
or you have any metal plates in your body.
你说什么
Excuse me?
粒子加速器泄露的能量
The stray energy from the accelerator
重新激活了钢梁的大脑  其实是部分大脑
reactivated Girder's brain-- well, parts of it, anyway.
所以我拆了我们的核磁共振仪组装了这个
So I disassembled our MRI machine to set up these--
电磁体阵列
electromagnets.
所以  当钢梁走进这扇门
So, when Girder walks through that door
困进由这些磁体产生的磁场中
and gets caught in the field that they generate,
可以扰乱把他
it should disrupt the energy wave
变成怪物的能量波
that turned him Abby Normal.
就像格式化硬盘一样
Like wiping a hard drive.
正是如此
Lah-kah-tah!
我只能维持全功率状态几秒钟
Okay, now, I can only maintain full power for a few seconds,
所以在他进屋之前我不能打开
so I can't actually turn this on until he's in the room.
他来了  你好啊
There he is. Hi!
怎么看起来不像是起作用了
Why don't it look like it's working?
因为就是没起作用  我们快离开这里
Because it's not. Uh, let's get out of here.
这是对她来说最安全的地方了
This is the safest place for her for now.
不够安全
Not safe enough.
计划A到G都没起作用
Plans A through G did not work.
我们现在有任何能阻止他的办法吗
Do we have anything in here that can stop him?
巴里可以  只要我们把他带回来
Barry could stop him if we could bring him back.
我们已经试过了  艾伦医生
We tried that already, Dr. Allen.
我们得再试试
We need to try it again.
总得有人试试什么办法
Somebody needs to try something.
那扇门扛不住的
That door's not gonna hold.
妈妈
Mom.
你好  巴里
Hi, Barry.
你不是我妈妈
You're not my mother.
你为什么要这么对我
Why are you doing this to me?
我们什么也没对你做  宝贝
We're not doing anything to you, sweetheart.
你只是太累了
You're just so tired.
坐吧  巴里  坐
Sit, Barry. Sit.
你一直是对的
You were right all along.
我没有接受
I haven't accepted it...
一刻都没有过
not for a second.
我觉得我永远也不会
I don't think I ever will.
我的好孩子
My beautiful boy...
你必须找个办法接受
you have to find a way.
该怎么做
How?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我知道这个
But I know this.
你变成了一个非常厉害的人
What you've become-- it's wonderful...
甚至是个奇迹
a miracle even,
但这不会阻止坏事发生在你身上
but it won't make bad things stop happening to you.
即便是闪电侠也无法逃脱
Even the Flash can't outrun the tragedies
宇宙在你前进道路上布满了的厄运
the universe is gonna keep sending your way.
你要接受这个事实
You have to accept that.
然后你就可以真正的自由奔跑了
And then you can truly run free.
我知道
I know.
我只是很想她
I just miss her.
我太想你了
I miss you so much.
如果我告诉你她很以你自豪呢
What if I told you that she's proud of you?
她为你所成为的人而自豪
And of the man that you've become?
到底是谁在告诉我
Who's telling me that...
是神速力  还是我的母亲
the Speed Force or my mother?
二者皆有
Both.
有什么其他出口能出去的吗
Is there any other way out of here?
没有  缺口房间是被设计成封闭的
No, the Breach Room was designed to be sealed off.
听着  如果他想要的是我
All right, look, if it's me that he wants,
-那我就去引开他  -不行
- I'll just lead him away. - No, you won't.
你甚至都走不出那扇门
You'll never even make it past that door.
如果他死而复生还想要你
If he came back from the dead and still wants you,
你为什么会觉得他会放你走
what makes you think he's gonna let you go now?
等等
Wait.
我看到巴里时  他脸上有种表情
I saw Barry. He had this look.
如果我们无法带他离开神速力
What if we couldn't get him out of the Speed Force
是因为他不想回来呢
because he didn't want to come back?
逃跑的恐龙
你还记得这本书吗
Do you remember this book?
它一直是你最喜欢的
It was always your favorite.
"曾经有一只小恐龙是只慈母龙"
"Once there was a little dinosaur called a Maiasaur,
"和母亲生活在一起"
"Who lived with his mother.
"有一天  他告诉他妈妈"
"One day, he told his mother,
"我真希望我像其他恐龙那样与众不同"
"I wish I were special like the other dinosaurs.
"如果我是霸王龙  我可以用我凶猛的牙撕咬"
If I were a T. Rex, I could chomp with my ferocious teeth!"
"但如果你是霸王龙"  他妈妈说
"But if you were a T. Rex,' said his mother,
"你要怎么用那瘦小的手臂拥抱我呢"
'how would you hug me with your tiny little arms?'"
"我希望我是迷惑龙"  小恐龙说道
"'I wish I were an Apatosaurus,' said the little dinosaur,
"这样用我的长脖子就可以看过树顶了"
"'so with my long neck I could see high above the treetops.'
"但如果你是迷惑龙"  他母亲说
"'But if you were an Apatosaurus,' said his mother,
"你在树顶上的时候  如何能听到"
"'how would you hear me in the treetops
"我在说我爱你呢"
"'when I told you I love you?
"是什么让你如此特殊呢  小慈母龙"
"What makes you so special, little Maiasaur?'
他母亲说道
"Said his mother.
"是你凶猛的牙齿或是长脖子或是尖嘴吗"
"'Is it your ferocious teeth or long neck or pointy beak?
"让你如此特殊的  是在这"
"'What makes you special is out of all
"宽阔世界中的所有不同恐龙之中"
"'of the different dinosaurs in the big, wide world,
"你有一位专属于你的母亲"
"'you have the mother who is just right for you
"而她将永远的"
and who will always'"...
"爱你"
"'Love you.'"
你准备好了
You're ready.
开始吧
Turn it on.
我们必须再试一次
We got to try again.
你们谁还有更好的办法吗
Any of you got a better idea?
当你看进神速力的时候
When you look into the Speed Force,
别人能一起看吗
can someone else see into it too?
只要你在拉蒙用震波的时候
Well, as long as you're in physical contact
和他有身体接触  那就...
with Ramon while he's vibing, then...
可以
yes.
让我来吧
Let me do that.
我可以把巴里带回来
I can get Barry to come back.
不
No.
让我来吧
Let me do it.
求你
Please.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
巴里
Barry.
巴里  和我回家吧
Barry, come home to me.
快跑  巴里  快跑
Run, Barry. Run.
巴里
Barry!
你回来了可真好  因为我们要死了
I'm so glad you're back, 'cause we're about to die.
等等  什么
Wait. What?
所以  钢梁
So... Girder.
钢梁复活了
Girder came back to life,
他现在变成了年轻的科学怪人
and he's all Young Frankenstein now,
而且他只认得爱瑞丝  她把他引到了工作室
and he only recognizes Iris, and she lured him to my workshop
好让我们给他消磁  但是机器短路了
so we could demagnetize him, but the machine shorted out,
所以他正要闯过那扇门
so he's about to come through that door
然后把我们都碾成莎莎酱
and smush us all into chunky salsa
还很有可能吸干我们的脑髓
and possibly eat our brains out.
我不知道  这还有待商榷
I don't know. Jury's still out on that.
好了  我知道了  我把他引到你工作室去
All right, I got it. I-I will lure him to your workshop,
然后我们找个办法重新接通电源  好吗
and we figure out a way to turn the power back on, okay?
计划H
Plan H.
托尼
Hey, Tony!
他带他走的远路  来吧
He's taking him the long way. Come on!
我希望你们准备好了  他快到了
I hope you're ready. He's almost here.
没有  没好呢
Nope, not ready.
供电最起码需要两块电磁铁
Power needs at least two electromagnets--
这电线根本撑不住
too much for this wiring to handle.
我们需要一条非常大的延长电线
We're gonna need a really big extension cord!
好吧  我看看我能做些什么
All right, I'll--I'll see what I can do.
巴里
Barry!
托尼  托尼
Tony, Tony...
我一直不怎么喜欢你
look, you were never my favorite person,
但让我们了解这一切吧
but let's end this...
这样你就可以安息了
so you can finally rest.
他在使用旋转来给电磁充能
He's using spin to charge the magnets.
就像一台涡轮发电机
Like an electric turbine.
抱歉  我迷路了
Sorry...I got lost.
没事的  我们找到了你
It's okay. We found you.
巴里
Barry.
你应该去休息  你不需要来这里
You should rest. You don't need to be here.
不  正相反  我想这里需要我
No, that's just it. I think I do.
我怎么在这里
How did I get here?
你怎么做到的
How did you do that?
你现在  会魔法了
Are you, like, magic now?
你早知会如此吗
Did you know that was gonna happen?
也许吧  很难解释  那是...
Maybe. It's hard to explain. It's...
是神速力
It's the Speed Force.
今天可真不得了啊
It's been quite a day, huh?
不是"破事接踵而来"
Not so much "One damn thing after anothe""
而是"所有破事都同时发生了"
as "every damn thing all at once"
还好最终都解决了
It all worked out okay in the end.
不  是你最终都解决了
No, you worked it out okay in the end.
真有趣  我从来没搞懂
It's funny. I never really understood
你的那一套"命运"论
where you were coming from with your whole "fate"
和"万事皆有因"的观点从何而来
and "everything happens for a reason" point of view.
但是现在...
But now...
我想或许是我错了
I think that maybe I was wrong.
我们身上所发生的一切...
Everything that's happened to us--
好事和坏事
good and bad--
成就了今天的我们
it made us who we are.
即使我有能力  我也不会去改变它
And I don't think that I would change it even if I could.
这么说有道理吗
Does that make any sense?
非常有道理
Perfect sense.
既然我们在谈论
And since we're on the subject
改变对于一些重要事情的看法
of changing our minds about important things,
你还记得我告诉你
you know that part where I told you
我要离开中城
I was gonna leave Central City
让你能够当好闪电侠
so that you could be the Flash
而不用每时每刻担心我的安危吗
without being concerned about me all the time?
全都忘掉吧  你摆脱不了我了
Forget all of that. You're stuck with me.
我哪里都不去了
I'm not going anywhere.
亲爱的妻子和母亲  诺拉·艾伦之墓
亲爱的妻子和母亲
诺拉·艾伦之墓
乔好几次都要带我来这里
Joe offered to take me so many times.
我总是找借口拒绝
I always found an excuse to say no.
亲爱的妻子和母亲
诺拉·艾伦之墓
我小时候  我妈妈会和我一起读这本书
My mom and I read this when I was little.
你知道这本书吗
Do you know it?
知道  我一直不喜欢那本书
Yeah. I-I never really liked that book.
为什么
Why?
因为那书讲的是一个母亲无论发生什么
Because it was about a mother who was always there
总相伴于她的孩子
for her child, no matter what,
我妈妈不是这样的...
and that wasn't my mom...
你的也不是
or yours.
我们都不曾拥有那个"专属"的人
We never had anyone who was "just right" for us.
我们真没有吗
Didn't we?
我现在看待事情的方式变了很多
I'm seeing things a lot differently now.
我浪费了太多时间
I wasted so much time
为自己所失去的东西而愤怒
being angry about what I'd lost
但我所拥有的更多...
when I had so much--
我爸  乔  还有你
my dad, Joe, and you.
说实话  爱瑞丝
The truth is, Iris,
我不知道我们之间这算什么
I don't know what this is between us
或是我们以后将何去何从
or where we go from here.
我只知道你是我的一切
All I know is you're everything to me,
而你永远都会是
and you always have been.
你的声音总能带我回家
And the sound of your voice will always bring me home.
凯特  拜托
Cait, please.
我让你不要这么叫我
I asked you not to call me that.
凯特琳...
Caitlin...
我们一直这样周旋着
we've been through this again and again,
毫无进展
and we've gotten nowhere.
现在我要知道  你是支持我
Now, I need to know-- are you with me,
还是要和我作对
or are you against me?
先别急着回答
Don't answer that yet.
我要去外面
I'm gonna go out there,
和我的朋友们聊会儿
spend a moment speaking to my friends,
我回来后  告诉我你的答案
and when I come back, you'll give me your answer.
如果你还在这里  那你就是选择和我在一起
If you're still here, I'll know you've chosen to stay with me.
但如果你不在这里...
But if you're not here...
我就会知道你选择了你的朋友们
I'll know you've chosen your friends instead.
而我下一次见面的时候
And I will show you exactly as much mercy as I will show them
我对你的仁慈将和对他们一样同等
when we next see each other.
就是这样
So there you have it.
我要走了
I need to go.
我的兄弟姐妹们...
My brothers and sisters...
我的朋友们...
my friends...
我带我们进入了这个新世界
I've brought us to this new world
它就在我们的脚下  毫无防备
which lay before us, defenseless,
供我们随意夺取
ours for the taking.
人类认为这个星球属于他们
The humans think that this planet belongs to them.
这是谁的世界
Whose world is this?
我们的世界
Our world! Our world!